CREATIVE DESIGNER / DEVELOPER

PERSONAL DETAILS

Mobile (+61) 0421 644 329

Emailjohnny_xu_1227@hotmail.comWebsitehttp://www.gaga-graphics.com

LinkedIn http://www.linkedin.com/in/johnnyxu

Github https://github.com/gaga1227

OVERVIEW

Creative Designer/Developer with more than 18 years of experience from digital agency, in-house and corporate environments in both Australia and China.

Talented and passionate about UI/UX engineering and new technologies in digital.

An organized perfectionist with great work ethic. Sharp attention to details and ambitions to create world-class works. Highly interested in working on UI/UX engineering, responsive web design and mobile/web applications with edge technologies.

SKILLS

Creative Art Direction

ALL DIFECTION

Digital Design (Web / Mobile)

Responsive Web Design

Interactive Design

Animation

Print Design

Illustration

Sketching / Drawing

Development

HTML / CSS / JavaScript (ES6)

TypeScript / Flow

Angular / React / Redux / Vue.js

GatsbyJS / GraphQL

jQuery / Lodash

AEM / Java / Node.js

Unit Test / E2E Test

Grunt / Gulp / Git / SVN

Sass / Less / BEM

Bootstrap / Foundation

Accessibility (WCAG)

Application & Others

UI / UX / Design Systems

Wireframing / Storyboarding

Information Architecture

Scrum / Kanban / CSM

Atlassian Suite

Adobe Suite / Sketch

Sound / Video Editing

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Web Engineer

flybuys (Loyalty Pacific) (JUL 2020 – DEC 2020) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Worked on transitioning of legacy public facing websites to React focused modern front-end stack (React, GatsbyJS, CSS Module, Storybook, Jest, GraphQL, Headless Drupal CMS).

Key Responsibilities

- Create and maintain internal front-end packages: UI components, Analytics, Utilities;
- Transform legacy web experience from Angular.js to React, GatsbyJS and Drupal CMS;
- Mentor junior team members, pair programming, code review;
- Manage and coordinate front-end web releases for multiple business streams;

Senior Front-end Development Consultant (Contract)

Morgan Consulting @ Latitude Financial Services (SEP 2019 – APR 2020) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Worked on public facing websites/brands across Australia and New Zealand with React focused front-end stack (React, GatsbyJS, Flow, Styled Components, Storybook).

Key Responsibilities

- Digital transformation: create, maintain, uplift UI components;
- Improve loan related products: customer acquisition, calculators, broker tools etc.;
- Support legacy code and products;
- Apply optimisations base on analytics data;

Senior Front-end Development Consultant (Contract)

RACV (FEB 2019 - AUG 2019) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Worked fullstack on AEM platform for UI/UX and components uplifting. Supporting wider development team and eCommerce solution (React 16 + AEM 6.3 + Magento 2).

Key Responsibilities

- Fullstack development of AEM components (new / uplifting);
- Establish and refine in-house development guidelines and practices;
- Introducing best UI/UX engineering practice and accessibility compliance support;
- Provide solution design, guidance and support for development team;
- Improving legacy code base and front-end build tools;
- Peer review / Code quality control / Knowledge sharing / Documentation;

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY (CONTINUED)

Front-end Development Consultant (Contract)

Australia Post (OCT 2017 - DEC 2018) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Worked on front-end experience enhancements for AEM based websites and web applications across different platforms for various stakeholders and domains from the business.

Software Developer, UI Developer

Sportsbet Pty Ltd (JUN 2014 - SEP 2017) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Worked on applications across desktop and mobile platforms from front-end web development to native Android app development, also with contributions to Back-End service APIs and applications.

Senior Interactive Developer

Fraynework Limited (MAY 2011 - MAY 2014) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Worked on Responsive Web Design, Mobile Web Development, Web App, Hybrid Mobile App, UI Development, CMS Front-end Modules for school communications, religious education and eLearning.

Creative Designer

FinPa New Media (JUL 2005 - APR 2011) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Worked on web, eLearning and multimedia resources across various industries.

Senior Designer

ETANG (DEC 2003 - JAN 2005) Shanghai, CHINA

Worked on marketing campaigns, communications, design and front-end development of etang.com - a major pioneer social media online community in China.

Interactive Designer

From-Zero Interactive Solutions (JAN 2003 - SEP 2003) Shanghai, CHINA

Worked on microsites, websites and digital advertising campaigns for major local and international brands. (Adidas, L'Oréal, Siemens, Toshiba, etc.)

EDUCATION

Master of Multimedia Design

Monash University (2005 - 2006) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Multimedia Design Theories and Techniques, Digital and Interaction Design, Business Practice for Multimedia Design

Bachelor of Artistic Design

Shanghai Jiao Tong University (1999 - 2003) Shanghai, CHINA

Fine Art, Graphic Design, Visual Communication, Visual Identity, Fundamental Branding and Advertising Theories

Certificate of Animation

Autodesk (2007) Sydney, AUSTRALIA

A 2-day Master Class held by Autodesk and Andrew Gordon from Pixar Animation Studios, on animation design and techniques.

AWARDS

2012 - 16th Annual Webby Awards Official Honouree

Together At One Altar

http://www.togetheratonealtar.catholic.edu.au

2006 - NEWWEBPICK (Flash Design and Technology)

Hunt Angels Official Movie Site

INTERESTS & INSPIRATIONS

Art, Design, Movies, Music, Video Games, Storytelling, Web and Technology, Photography, Food and Cooking

LANGUAGES

English (Fluent), Chinese (Native)

RECOMMENDATIONS

"During his time at Fraynework Johnny has proven to be a true leader in front-end development and has constantly risen to every challenge that has been thrown his way. Johnny has a terrific eye for detail and truly excels in the areas of interaction design, responsive web design and mobile web development. He also has a terrific work ethic and a curious nature, which has made him a delight to work with and a pivotal member of our team. In addition to completing all of his projects with a high level of quality and a minimum of fuss, Johnny has also provided leadership within the team and provided a great deal of assistance to other developers and designers and helped grow the capacity of the group."

Steve Darmody Director of Interactive Media, Fraynework Limited

managed Johnny since 2011

"Johnny made animated banner ads and graphics for Oodles on a number of occasions. I found him to interpret the briefs with a creative mind set and thereby improving on the original concept. Also very timely and the quality of the finished artwork and graphics were always of high quality. I recommend Johnny to others seeking creativity, quality and value for money."

Steve Sherlock Founder, Oodles.com

hired Johnny as a Graphic/Web Designer in 2009

"I have worked with Johnny in the development of educational multimedia products. He is an outstanding designer and has a great ability to translate the client's design requirements and brief into the end design. I highly recommend him for creative design roles."

Rachel Kennedy The Le@rning Federation

hired Johnny as a Graphic/Web Designer in 2008

REFEREES

Available upon request.